Right.
It's time to get down to business.
So our game's looking nice, but there is a major feature which we have ignored and that is crash detection,
because right now we can just ski to our heart's content.
And if we hit into a tree, well, that's not going to stop us.
And that would be fun to do in real life.
Um, but we doesn't work like that in real life, so it shouldn't work like that in our game.
So in this lesson we are going to fix that.
So let's create a new script that will detect if we have crashed into a tree or not.
So on our main sprite, it's standard procedure.
We can move in a when flag clicked a forever and an if condition.
Now we can move over to our sensing, bring in this touching check block and change it to detect our
tree sprite.
Then if this condition is true, we can just add a simple stop all so our game will stop if we hit any
trees.
So giving that a play.
As you can see, we are skiing along nicely.
Next thing, if we hit into any trees, well they all disappear.
So this is something that works.
But as you can clearly see, there are definitely a few issues here.
The first being that our trees disappear and the stop is so sudden.
And the second issue is how sensitive this code is, as if we just nick into the side of our tree.
Our game stops.
So the first issue we will ignore for now is we will look at a great way to solve that in the next lesson.
So let's focus on the second issue, which is how our code is just too sensitive.
And here is your mini challenge here.
I want you to try and find a solution to our stop or script only triggers.
If we touch the tree for more than a 0.2 seconds.
So pause this video now and give this a go.
How can you implement it so it only triggers the stop?
Or if we've touched the tree for more than 0.2 seconds.
Well, let's see how it's done.
So thankfully, the solution to this problem is quite simple.
Just requires a bit of creative thinking.
And here all you need to do is select this.
If check, hit duplicate, remove the stop all, then move this back into the script and then we can
grab a white block.
And here we can stick it in between these two if checks.
And lastly we can change it to 0.2 seconds.
Now if you look at the script it basically checks to see if we are touching a tree or a rock.
And if we are, it waits 0.2 seconds and then checks again.
And if we are still touching it, then we lose.
So it's as simple as that.
This basically means making the crash detection less sensitive.